Waleed Mohammed Althabit

Business Planning & Analysis Expert

w.thabit.90@gmail.com +966553277377 Riyadh, Saudi Arabia





RESUME OBJECTIVE

Senior business and technology expert with 10+ years of working experience seeking a leading role to leverage my skills and abilities to supervise organizational functions and resources. Desire to contribute to achieving strategic objectives, increasing productivity and motivating performance.

EDUCATION

Master Degree / Business Administration (ft Class Distinction)

King Saud University, Riyadh 2020 - 2022

Bachelor Degree / Electrical Engineering

King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Dhahran 2007 - 2012

EXPERIENCE

Strategic Projects Manager - Saudi Telecom Company (stc) / 2021 - Present

Responsible for overseeing the execution of corporate growth portfolio and managing the executive reporting to top management ensuring accurate and timely updates of programs status supporting decision taking as well as to provide consultations to their management team in planning and executing different initiatives by reviewing and advising on scope, implementation plans and KPIs.

Technology Planning & Performance Supervisor - Saudi Telecom Company (stc) / 2019 - 2021

Managing & controlling the delivery of sector deliverables to corporate strategic cross-functional programs & projects as well as supporting in planning the sector BSC KPIs and monitoring the progress toward ensuring achieving targets.

HR Business Partner - Saudi Telecom Company (stc) / 2016 - 2019

Managing the delivery of HR strategic products to beneficiary sectors through partnering with their executives to align HR to their strategy and ensure its effectiveness toward enabling business success.

Project Management Specialist - Saudi Telecom Company (stc) / 2015 - 2016

Handling the control & monitoring of corporate portfolios of consultancy projects & programs by following up with involved stakeholders and ensuring objectives delivery according to agreed budget and timeline.

Testing & Validation Engineer - Advanced Electronics Company (AEC) / 2012 - 2014

Carrying out testing procedures & their automation to ensure efficient production of company products with their full specifications.

Training & Certificates

Key Performance Indicator Professional (KPI-P).

Six Sigma Yellow Belt.

Project Management Professional (PMP).

CIPD Level 3 Diploma.

CIPD HR Business Partnering.

Business & Competitive Intelligence Management.

Gamification of Retail Use Cases - TJ Program.

Use Cases Management Using Best Practices.

Practical Data Science/Data Engineering.

Design Thinking SIG Program.

Digitization SIG Program.

Artificial Intelligence Application & Practices.

Strategic Workforce Planning.

Delloite HR Business Partner Program.

Performance Management.

Languages

Arabic and English well spoken and written.

Honors & Awards

Certification of Appreciation for Outstanding Performance. (stc)

HRBP Capability Building Program Top Performer. (stc)

HR Innovate Contest Award Winner. (stc)

Certification of Appreciation for ADDAD-5 Project. (AEC)

Professional Strengths

Ability to meet deadlines and handles multi-tasks.

Well-developed verbal and written communication skills.

Team management and leadership.

Analytics and data management skills.

Creative in design thinking and problem solving.

Ability to conduct researches and presentations.

Work effectively both individual and as part of a team.

Computer Skills

Experienced with Microsoft Office Tools.

Knowledge in Project Management Tools.

Programming skills in C++, MATLAB.